Patrick Simpson

Washington State 253-359-0432 patrick.simpson215@ gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/ PatrickSimpsonIT

Summary

I'm a problem solver with five years of experience in large enterprise logistics, and demonstrable increasing responsibility in any given role. I'm working to pivot from logistics management to information technology and have a passion for cyber security.

Experience

Student, CPTC, 2019-2020

- Earned an associates degree, Computer Networking and Information Systems Security
- Enrolled in OSCP course, the PWK, to work towards practical certificate

Engineering Supervisor, UPS 2019

- Managed a team of up to 5 mechanics
- Managed work order system to prioritize projects and work tickets
- Coordinated and lead meetings, created and distributed training material to retrain internal employees to resolve handling and maintenance issues
- Used Excel to analyze data in package flow and find issues in operations before they became issues
- Handled internal requests for equipment, working with vendors to complete projects across more than seven facilities in western Washington and more in Montana
- Followed up on projects and ensured internal satisfaction
- Handled invoicing for projects and spending
- Oversaw activation of contingency plans for power failures and building breakdowns
- Managed break-fix responses and routine maintenance
- Controlled a large inventory for on site maintenance and repairs, reordering and counting stock
- Responded to emergency breakdowns to bring operations back online as fast as possible
- Worked under pressure juggling multiple deadlines while maintaining documentation on breakdowns to ensure thorough work

Operations Supervisor UPS 2016-2019

- Managed up to 10 employees between productive and clerical operations
- Reduced labor hours of international department by up to 40% by working with regional management to improve automation systems at my building
- Coordinated and held meetings with other management employees to address failures in hazardous materials handling, creating and distributed training material to assist in retraining of employees
- Managed employees performing customer support, working to resolve higher level customer problems
- Managed a team of hazardous material auditors, worked with customers to help them find and resolve issues, saving both the company and customers money
- Managed a team of international audit employees, working with customers to resolve problems in transit or shipping
- Ran operations during breakdowns and power outages
- Worked with an HMI system to manage automation and package flow of building
- Used Excel to analyze data and find issues in international packages before they became issues

Clerk, UPS 2014-2016

- Found resolutions to customer issues, handled outgoing calls to resolve issues
- Audited international packages for regulatory requirements
- Audited hazardous materials packages for regulatory requirements
- Organized and controlled an inventory of up to 200 outgoing packages
- Juggled multiple deadlines nightly to deliver optimal customer resolutions

Skills & Interests

Skills

- Project Management
- Customer service
- Computer Hardware
- TCP/IP Networking
- Windows Server Administration
- Linux Administration
- Bash Scripting
- Conflict Resolution

Interests/Hobbies

- Custom PC building I have a thermaltake P3 open air case with some AIO liquid coolers
- PC games
- Creative Writing

Education

Pierce County Skills Center 2012-2014

- Learned the basics of software programming
- Learned C++
- Engaged in hands on training working towards compTIA A+ certificate
- Troubleshooted and repaired computers

Clover Park Technical College 2019-2020

- Completed project oriented, hands on degree in information security
- Built fully functional networks including firewalls, SIEM systems, Mail and name servers, active directory and linux file servers
- Participated in simulated threat hunting, using SIEM systems to detect and block intrusion attempts from my peers
- Built and configured physical, racked cisco devices
- Used virtualization and colocation, including ESXi and HyperV on baremetal